<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Leaf Disease app</string>
    <string name="info">Infomation on Health of the plant</string>
    <string name="cure">Cure of the Illness</string>

    <string name="default_disease_info">Invalid</string>
    <string name="default_cure_info">Invalid</string>

    <string name="early_blight_info">Early blight in potato leaves is a common fungal disease caused by Alternaria solani. It typically thrives in warm, humid environments, especially when temperatures range between 24°C and 29°C. The disease primarily affects older leaves, where it presents as dark brown spots with characteristic concentric rings, giving a target-like appearance. These lesions are often surrounded by a yellow halo and can grow larger, sometimes merging with others, eventually causing significant leaf blight. While it mainly impacts foliage, it can also affect stems and, in rare cases, tubers. The fungus survives in infected plant debris and tubers, and it spreads through spores that are dispersed by wind, rain, or physical contact. Detection is commonly done through visual symptoms, microscopic examination of fungal spores, or PCR-based tests to identify the fungal DNA.</string>
    <string name="early_blight_cure">To treat early blight in potato plants, farmers can use a mix of good farming habits and sprays. They should rotate crops each year, clean up dead plant leaves after harvest, and avoid watering the leaves directly to stop the fungus from spreading. Planting potato types that are less likely to get the disease also helps. Spraying fungicides like chlorothalonil or mancozeb at the right time protects the plants, and switching between different sprays prevents the fungus from getting used to them. Giving plants enough space, trimming lower leaves, and keeping them healthy with proper water and nutrients makes them stronger and less likely to get sick.</string>

    <string name="fungal_diseases_info">Fungal diseases on potato leaves are caused by various types of fungi that thrive in moist and warm conditions. These diseases often show up as dark spots, patches, or powdery growth on the leaves, which can spread quickly if not managed. The fungi usually enter through wounds or wet leaf surfaces and damage the plant\'s ability to photosynthesize, which weakens the plant and reduces potato yield. Common fungal diseases affecting potatoes include early blight, late blight, and powdery mildew, each with its own symptoms but similar in how they infect and spread.</string>
    <string name="fungal_diseases_cure">To manage and cure fungal diseases on potato leaves, farmers often use a combination of methods. Crop rotation helps reduce the buildup of fungal spores in the soil. Removing and destroying infected plants or leaves early can prevent the disease from spreading. Ensuring good air circulation by proper spacing of plants and avoiding overhead watering can keep leaves dry and less prone to infection. Fungicides, especially those containing copper or other antifungal chemicals, are commonly used to treat and prevent fungal infections. It’s also important to plant disease-resistant potato varieties whenever possible.</string>

    <string name="healthy_info">Good news, This Plant is Healthy</string>
    <string name="healthy_cure">No Cure required</string>

    <string name="late_blight_info">Late blight is a serious disease of potato leaves caused by the water mold Phytophthora infestans. It thrives in cool, moist conditions and spreads rapidly, leading to dark brown or black spots on leaves and stems, which can destroy entire crops if not controlled. The disease also affects tubers, causing them to rot both in the field and in storage.</string>
    <string name="late_blight_cure">To manage late blight, farmers should remove and destroy infected plants, avoid overhead irrigation, and ensure proper spacing for air flow. Using certified disease-free seed potatoes and practicing crop rotation help reduce the risk. Fungicides like those containing mancozeb, chlorothalonil, or metalaxyl are commonly used to prevent and control the spread. Choosing resistant potato varieties also strengthens long-term protection.</string>

    <string name="plant_pests_info">Plant pests on potato leaves, like aphids, flea beetles, and Colorado potato beetles, can cause significant damage. These pests feed on potato plants by piercing leaves and sucking out sap, which weakens the plant and can introduce diseases. Common signs of plant pest damage include holes or discoloration on leaves, wilting, and stunted growth. Pest infestations may also lead to the spread of viral and fungal diseases. Regular inspection of plants, especially during warm months, can help detect pests early.</string>
    <string name="plant_pests_cure">To manage and cure plant pest damage on potato leaves, it\'s important to implement a combination of methods. Using insecticides such as neem oil or pyrethrins can effectively reduce pest populations. In cases of larger infestations, manual removal, especially for pests like Colorado potato beetles, is useful. Introducing natural predators, such as ladybugs for aphids, can help control pest numbers in an eco-friendly way. Additionally, crop rotation disrupts the lifecycle of pests, preventing recurrence, while trap crops can divert pests from the main potato plants. Regular monitoring and a mix of these strategies can significantly reduce pest damage, ensuring healthy potato growth.</string>

    <string name="potato_cyst_nematode_info">Potato cyst nematode (PCN) is a serious soil-borne pest that affects potato crops. These microscopic worms, particularly Globodera rostochiensis and Globodera pallida, infect the roots of potato plants. They form cysts around their eggs, which can survive in the soil for many years. As the nematodes invade the roots, they cause stunted growth, yellowing of leaves, and reduced tuber yield. The damage can be severe, leading to poor-quality potatoes and significant crop loss.</string>
    <string name="potato_cyst_nematode_cure">To manage potato cyst nematodes, crop rotation is one of the most effective methods, as nematodes have specific host plants. Resistant potato varieties are also available and can be planted in infected areas to minimize damage. Solarization, which involves using plastic to heat the soil and kill nematodes, and soil fumigation with nematicides can also reduce nematode populations. Ensuring clean seed potatoes and avoiding the spread of contaminated soil can further help in controlling PCN. Regular soil testing can monitor the presence of nematodes and guide management strategies.</string>

    <string name="potato_virus_info">Potato Virus is a group of viruses that can infect potato plants, causing significant damage to crops. The most common potato viruses include Potato Virus Y (PVY), Potato Leafroll Virus (PLRV), and Potato Virus X (PVX). These viruses are primarily spread through aphids, mechanical damage, and infected seed potatoes. Symptoms of virus infection include yellowing of leaves, stunted growth, and deformed tubers. Infected plants may show a reduced yield, and the quality of the potatoes can be compromised, especially with issues like poor size and uneven texture.</string>
    <string name="potato_virus_cure">To control potato viruses, it is important to use virus-free seed potatoes, as they are the main source of viral infection. Crop rotation and controlling aphid populations through insecticides or natural predators can help prevent the spread of the virus. In some cases, resistant potato varieties may be planted to reduce the impact of the virus. Regular monitoring of plants for early signs of infection can also aid in early detection and the implementation of control measures before significant damage occurs.</string>
</resources>
